Welcome to our training on how to determine product weights and dimensions.
Getting the right product measurements can be tricky.
So it's important that you understand how to measure them accurately.
In this video, we'll discuss the importance of accurate product measurements,
how fulfillment centers do their measurements, and how to avoid mismatch,
how to measure weight such as dimensional weight and scale weight,
and how to measure dimension and volume.
By the end of this video, you should know how to measure a product's weight,
measure a product's dimensions, and avoid discrepancies between your and fulfillment center measurements.
Item package weight and dimensions refer to the weight and dimensions of an individual product or
item
that you're listing under a fulfillment network SKU or FNSKU.
The weight and dimensions also include the item's packaging, such as a box or poly bag.
An item, item, package, and case can all have specific weights and dimensions.
Fees for fulfillment by Amazon or FBA are then calculated based on item package weight and dimensions.
Let's review how Amazon measures products in our fulfillment centers.
Amazon uses multiple sensors installed throughout our fulfillment centers to capture item measurements.
The sensors capture your item packaging edge to edge, including loose materials
such as plastic bags and loose parts such as handles.
The most common cause of differences between seller and fulfillment center measurements
is the type of packaging material in use.
To minimize discrepancies between the dimensions you expect
and the dimensions captured by fulfillment center sensors,
make sure that the packaging is uniform in size across your units
and that it doesn't show loose material or bulges.
Use tight fitting or vacuum sealed poly bags,
taping down flaps, and avoiding packaging that easily bulges
can help prevent dimension variation.
Let's take a look at how to determine a product's dimensions.
To replicate potential sensor measurements,
take a single item package with the item inside as it would be received by a customer.
On a flat surface, fully extend loose packaging materials such as poly bag flaps and package handles
to capture the maximum item package dimensions.
Measure the item package's longest edge as its length,
its second longest edge as its width, and its shortest edge as its height.
If one or more of these dimensions differs across the package, such as a bulge,
measure the longest or thickest part of that dimension.
To determine your item's girth, add its median length to its shortest length
and multiply by two.
To determine your item's girth plus length, add its girth and its longest length.
Let's take a look at measuring weight in a product.
Amazon uses two different types of weight, unit weight and dimensional weight.
Unit weight is determined by how much a single unit of your item package weighs when placed on a
scale.
Dimensional weight is calculated using your item package's dimensions.
To calculate dimensional weight, multiply the package's overall length, width, and height, then
divide by 139.
For any apparel items that have a unit weight of 3/4 of a pound or less,
any non-apparel small standard items and any special oversize items, only unit weight is used in
fee calculation.
For apparel items, dimensional weight may apply when calculating fees for items that are standard
size
and weigh more than 3/4 of a pound or are oversized but not considered special oversize.
For non-apparel items, dimensional weight fees may also apply if the item is large standard size
but not small standard size or if the item is oversized but not considered special oversize.
A standard size item is one that meets all of the following criteria when fully packaged.
Unit weight that is less than or equal to 20 pounds.
The length is less than or equal to 18 inches.
The width is less than or equal to 14 inches.
And the height is less than or equal to 8 inches.
A small standard size item is one that meets all of the following criteria when fully packaged.
The length is less than or equal to 15 inches.
The width is less than or equal to 12 inches.
And the height is less than or equal to 3/4 of an inch.
The greater of dimensional weight and unit weight is used to calculate fees for any item that's
eligible to receive dimensional weight.
Now let's review what you've learned so far.
In this video, we've covered the importance of accurate product measurements,
how fulfillment centers take measurements and how to avoid mismatches,
how to measure weight such as dimensional weight and scale weight,
and how to measure dimensions and volume.
This concludes our training on how to determine product weights and dimensions.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.